https://www.needco.com/r/en/policies-terms/privacy-policy

Privacy Policy | NorthEast Electrical
Privacy Policy
Product Comparison
The maximum number of products that can be compared is 4. Please refine your selection.
OK
Your session is about to timeout due to inactivity.
Click OK to extend your time for an additional 0 minutes.
OK
This item has been successfully added to your list.
0
The item has been added to your cart.
Miscellaneous Fasteners
PVF (Pipes, Valves, Fittings)
Staples
PVF (Pipes, Valves, Fittings)
Lamps
Compact Fluorescent Lamp (CFL)
NM Non-Metallic Sheathed Cables
Photovoltaic Wires (PV)
Update Your Browser
For the best experience on the NorthEast Electrical Site we recommend using one of the below browsers. Please go to one of these sites and get the latest version of the browser:
Google Chrome
Mozilla Firefox
Microsoft Edge
Home
Policies & Terms
Privacy Policy
Policies & Terms
Copyright
Privacy Policy
Return Procedures and Policy
Terms and Conditions
PRIVACY POLICY
EFFECTIVE DATE: JULY 1, 2020
INTRODUCTION, SCOPE AND ACCEPTANCE
Sonepar Management US, Inc. (“Sonepar”) and its various affiliates, subsidiaries and locally managed electrical and industrial distributors, including but not limited to, Capital Lighting and Supply, LLC, Codale Energy Services & Supply, LLC, CooperFriedman Electric Supply Co., Inc., Crawford Electric Supply Company, Inc., Independent Electric Supply Inc., North Coast Electric Company, OneSource Distributors LLC, QED, Inc., Sonepar Distribution New England, Inc., Stuart C. Irby Company, Vallen Distribution, Inc.,
Viking Electric Supply, Inc. and World Electric Supply, Inc. (collectively, “Company”), is a leader in business-to business distribution of electrical, industrial and safety products and related solutions (“Products and Services”). The purpose of this privacy policy (“Policy”) is to let you know how we handle the information collected through the use of the websites located at SoneparUSA.com, capitalelectricsupply.com, codale.com, cooper-electric.com, crawfordelectricsupply.com, iesupply.com, irby.com, northcoast.com, needco.com, 1sourcedist.com, qedelectric.com, vallen.com, vikingelectric.com, worldelectricsupply.com, or any website owned, operated, licensed or controlled by Company (the “Website”). This Policy applies solely to the information that we collect through the Website. As Company provides its Products and Services to businesses, not individual consumers, the Website is intended only for businesses and their representatives. As used in this Policy, terms such as “we”, “us” or “our” to refer to Company.
By using the Website, including registering an account via the Website related in any manner to Company, you consent to this Privacy Policy in your capacity as a business or an employee, officer, director, contractor or representative of a business. If you do not agree to the terms of this Policy, please do not use the Website. Your continued use of the Website following the posting of changes to these terms will mean that you accept those changes.
COLLECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
You can browse the Website without telling us who you are or revealing any personally identifiable information. If you choose to become a customer of Company, register for an account, and choose to provide personally identifiable information through registration via the Website, such as your name, address, telephone number, cell phone number, e-mail address or fax number as related to your business (“Personal Information”), we will use that information and may share it with other companies and/or individuals (e.g., our partners, consultants, and service providers) for the business purpose for which you submitted it to us, such as to respond to your inquiry or to provide you with information that you requested. You do not have to provide us with Personal Information; however, this may limit your ability to use some functions of this Website or to request additional services or information through the Website.
USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
Our primary purpose in collecting Personal Information is to provide you, as a customer, with access to our sites and/or use of our Products and Services, provide requested customer service and relevant information about your account, and to provide you, as a customer, with an efficient and customized experience which can be enhanced in the future, promotions and a loyalty program. If you choose to provide us with Personal Information through the Website and/or registering an account with us as a customer, we use your Personal Information for a number of purposes such as:
To customize, measure and improve our services, content and advertising.
To contact you, either via email or telephone to inform you, the customer, about our services and those of our corporate family, deliver targeted marketing, service updates, and promotional offers based on the customer’s communication preferences.
To provide you with other services requested by your business as described when we collect the information.
To comply with applicable laws, regulations, and legal process.
To protect our rights, the rights of affiliates or related third parties, or take appropriate legal action.
To keep a record of our transactions and communications.
To notify you of changes to this Policy.
As otherwise necessary or useful for us to conduct our business, so long as such use is permitted by law.
DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
Company does not sell Personal Information, but may share data, including Personal Information, as described in this Policy.
Business Transfers.
We may share Personal Information with other business entities if all or part of Company’s business is sold, merged, assigned, dissolved, acquired, or transferred in a similar transaction to such business entity. We will require any such successor business entity to honor the terms of this Policy.
Disclosures Under Special Circumstances.
We may share information about you in response to a court order, subpoena, search warrant, law or regulation. We may cooperate with law enforcement authorities in investigating and prosecuting activities that are illegal, violate our rules, or may be harmful to other visitors. In such circumstances, we will take appropriate measures to ensure that the requester understands the sensitive nature of the Personal Information that they may receive.
Disclosures to Third Parties Assisting In Our Operations.
We may also share Personal Information with other third-party companies that we collaborate with or hire to perform services on our behalf. As an example, we may hire a company to help us send and manage email, and we might provide the company with your email address and certain other information in order for them to send you an email message on our behalf. Similarly, we may hire companies to host or operate some of our websites and related computers and software applications. We contractually require such third-party service providers to protect the privacy and security of Personal Information in a manner consistent with this Policy.
AUTOMATICALLY COLLECTED INFORMATION AND ANONYMOUS INFORMATION
Each time you visit the Website, Company collects some information to improve the overall quality of the online experience.
Aggregated Data.
Company collects aggregate queries for internal reporting and also counts, tracks, and aggregates your activity into Company’s analysis of general traffic-flow at the Website.
To these ends, Company may merge information into aggregated group data.
In some cases, Company may remove personal identifiers from Personal Information and maintain it in aggregate form that may later be combined with other information to generate anonymous, aggregated statistical information. Such anonymous, group data may be shared on an aggregated basis with Company’s affiliates, business partners, service providers and/or vendors.
Web Server Logs and IP Addresses.
An Internet Protocol (“IP”) address is a number that automatically identifies the computer or device you have used to access the Internet. The IP address enables our server to send you the web pages that you want to visit, and it may disclose the server owned by your Internet Service Provider. Company may use IP addresses to conduct Website analyses and performance reviews and to administer the Website.
Cookies and Web Beacons.
Periodically, some pages on this Website may use “cookies,” which are small files that the site places on your hard drive for identification purposes. These files are used for site registration and customization the next time you visit us. You should note that cookies cannot read data off of your hard drive. Your web browser may allow you to be notified when you are receiving a cookie, giving you the choice to accept it or not. You can also refuse all cookies by turning them off in your browser. By not accepting cookies, some pages may not fully function and you may not be able to access certain information on this Website.
Information that we collect through cookies includes (i) the name and version of the operating system on your computer, (ii) the name and version of your browser, (iii) which page on the site you are currently reading, as well as clicks and time spent on a particular page, (iv) if you were sent to the current page by some other page on the web, the universal resource locator (“URL”) of the referring web page, and (v) geolocation of your computer or device.
Some of the site’s web pages may use web beacons in conjunction with cookies to compile aggregate statistics about site usage.
A web beacon is an electronic image (also referred to as an “action tag,” “single-pixel,” or “clear GIF”) that is commonly used to track the traffic patterns of users from one web page to another in order to maximize web traffic flow and to otherwise analyze the effectiveness of the Website.
Some web beacons may be unusable if you elect to reject their associated cookies.
THIRD PARTY WEBSITES AND SERVICES
We may provide on the Website links to the sites of some of our partners and their products and services if we think their business may be of interest to our customers. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of those websites, and we recommend that you review the privacy policies of each website that you visit. When you select a link to a third-party website from this Website, you will be leaving the Company website. Any information that you disclose on the third-party website will be governed by that website’s privacy policy.
RESPONSE TO “DO NOT TRACK” SIGNALS
Some Internet browsers include the ability to transmit “Do Not Track” signals.
Since uniform standards for “Do Not Track” signals have not yet been adopted, Company does not process or respond to “Do Not Track” signals.
CHILDREN’S PRIVACY PROTECTION
Under Age 13.
Company understands the importance of protecting children’s privacy in the interactive online world.
This website is not designed for, or intentionally targeted at, children under 13 years of age.
It is not our policy to intentionally collect or maintain information about anyone under the age of 13.
No one under the age of 13 should submit any Personal Information to Company or this website.
Under Age 18.
Minors under 18 years of age may have the Personal Information that they have provided to Company through this website deleted by sending an email to the email listed at the end of this Policy requesting deletion.
Please note that, while we make reasonable efforts to comply with such requests, deletion of your Personal Information does not ensure complete and comprehensive removal of the data from all systems.
COMMUNICATION PRACTICES
We may send electronic newsletters, notification of account status, and other communications, such as marketing communications, on a periodic basis to various individuals and organizations. We may also send email communications regarding topics such as Website updates. We offer you appropriate consent mechanisms, such as opt-out, for marketing and certain other communications (i.e., commercial email or text messages). As examples, you may opt-out as provided for in a specific email communication or contact us as described below in the section “Contact Us.” Please be aware that opt-outs may not apply to certain types of communications, such as account status, Website updates, or other communications.
GLOBAL PRIVACY STANDARDS
Company strives to comply with all applicable laws globally that are designed to protect our customer’s privacy. Although legal requirements may vary from country to country, Company intends to adhere to the principles set forth in this Policy even when transferring our customer’s information between countries that may not require the same level of privacy protection.
THIRD PARTY ONLINE ADVERTISING
Some of the advertisements you may see on the Website are delivered by third parties who also collect information through their own cookies, web beacons and other similar technologies about your online activities, either on our services or across the Internet, in an effort to understand your interests and deliver advertisements that are tailored to your interests. These third parties include advertisers, advertising agencies and ad networks that may collect information about you when you view or interact with one of their advertisements and may collect information about your online activities over time and across different websites. Company does not have access to the information these third parties may collect about your interests to deliver relevant advertising to you, and the information practices of these third parties are not covered by this Policy. These companies may offer a way for you to choose not to have your information used for advertising purposes. For more information about third-party advertising networks and similar entities that use these technologies, see www.aboutads.info/consumers, and to opt-out of such ad networks’ and services’ advertising practices, go to www.aboutads.info/choices. Once you click the link, you may choose to opt-out of such advertising from all participating advertising companies or only advertising provided by specific advertising companies.
SOCIAL MEDIA POLICY
We encourage you to read, share, follow us and provide commentary on any of our social media sites. If you do choose to share information about your experience with Company on our social media sites, you acknowledge this social media policy. Please be aware that by "Liking" or sharing content about the Company using the social sharing mechanism, you agree to allow Company to list the name, photo, etc. associated with the social media profiles. This information may be viewable to your social networks, depending on your privacy settings. We reserve the right on our social media sites to edit comments for content, remove off-topic contributions, delete offensive comments or remarks, block offensive contributors and/or delete actual or suspected spam content. We reserve the right to respond to any post or user content on our social media sites, and may occasionally privately request your contact information to assist offline with your consent by routing the matter to the appropriate persons or department for further handling. Please be aware that once you post something online, there is the potential for numerous individuals to read your words, even years from now. Therefore, we suggest that you exercise caution when posting on any social media sites, and that you not disclose personally identifiable information.
DATA SECURITY
We maintain reasonable administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to help prevent Personal Information from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorized way, altered or disclosed. While Company has endeavored to create a secure and reliable website for users, the confidentiality of any communication or material transmitted to/from the Website or via e-mail cannot be guaranteed.
CHANGES TO THIS POLICY
This Policy may be revised from time to time as we add new features and services, as laws change, and as industry privacy and security best practices evolve.
We display an effective date on the Policy so that it will be easier for you to know when there has been a change.
If we make any change to this Policy regarding use or disclosure of Personal Information, we will provide appropriate notice and choices to you, on this Website and in other appropriate locations (including email), based on the scope and extent of changes. Small changes or changes that do not significantly affect individual privacy interests may be made at any time and without prior notice.
FOR ADDITIONAL INFORMATION/CONTACT US
If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Policy and our related privacy practices, Company policy can be reached using any listed contact information on the Website or affiliated sites as well as by email at privacy@sonepar-us.com, or by postal mail at:
Sonepar Management US, Inc.
*Same Day or Next Day Delivery available on most orders, to most areas.
© 2020 NorthEast Electrical
